<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Arran's Github Pages on Arrans Technical blog</title><link>https://arran4.github.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Arran's Github Pages on Arrans Technical blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 11:50:17 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://arran4.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Git Bash and WSL on Windows Terminal Preview vs IntelliJ</title><link>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/011-git-bash-and-wsl-on-windows-terminal-preview-vs-intellij/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 10:03:29 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/011-git-bash-and-wsl-on-windows-terminal-preview-vs-intellij/</guid><description>For some reason IntelliJ and Windows terminal discover available shells in different ways, but either way is not ideal. (In-fact IntelliJ uses two different means of discovery.)
The terminal popup in Intellj seems to be unaware of Gitbash..
Which is in complete contrast to the terminal settings (same plugin) which is unaware of my WSL deployments. (Possibly because it&amp;rsquo;s using a file path based system) Which means I can&amp;rsquo;t set Debian WSL as my default terminal in IntelliJ.</description></item><item><title>Goland Refactor Dialog</title><link>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/010-goland-refactor-dialog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 17:17:26 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/010-goland-refactor-dialog/</guid><description>Another one from the department of should have been a bug issue: Why doesn&amp;rsquo;t the Goland &amp;ldquo;move&amp;rdquo; dialog show you the receiver. When you&amp;rsquo;re implementing a new interface this can make it a bit hard to use when you start to refactor your code.
-_-</description></item><item><title>Linux, Dmesg, and Issue Reporting</title><link>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/009-linux-dmesg-and-issue-reporting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 22:19:37 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/009-linux-dmesg-and-issue-reporting/</guid><description>So started using linux.. Getting this issue here:
[ 499.624767] thinkpad_acpi: unhandled HKEY event 0x6031 [ 499.624771] thinkpad_acpi: please report the conditions when this event happened to ibm-acpi-devel@lists.sourceforge.net [ 517.509897] thinkpad_acpi: unhandled HKEY event 0x6031 [ 517.509905] thinkpad_acpi: please report the conditions when this event happened to ibm-acpi-devel@lists.sourceforge.net I really don&amp;rsquo;t want to have to mail a mailing list and learn how to engage with the community, how to write a post, and worst yet, having to subscribe to a mailing list to get a single response.</description></item><item><title>KDE and Changing Mouse Scroll Speed</title><link>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/008-kde-and-changing-mouse-scroll-speed/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 22:02:12 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/008-kde-and-changing-mouse-scroll-speed/</guid><description>So.. Turns out the control pannel mess that exists on Windows is contagious. After 2 years of using Windows (because of driver issues) I have finally been able to switch back to Linux.. However I got used to a couple settings. One was a faster mouse scroll speed&amp;hellip; So I go to configure that and this is what I see: A quick google got me here: https://forum.kde.org/viewtopic.php?t=160416
Ugh no difference</description></item><item><title>Lenovo, Ubuntu Upgrade, and the Backport Iwlwifi Dkms Package</title><link>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/007-lenovo-ubuntu-upgrade-and-the-backport-iwlwifi-dkms-package/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 21:36:08 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/007-lenovo-ubuntu-upgrade-and-the-backport-iwlwifi-dkms-package/</guid><description>Had an issue with getting MOK to install my keys for my Intel Corporation Wi-Fi 6 AX200 (rev 1a) wireless card on my Lenovo X1 Carbon Extreme G2.. Turns out there is a bug in the shell script that installs the self signed keys in to MOX&amp;hellip; Which is great. But it turns out I have hit a bug..
Perhaps this is because I use zsh or somee other reason but.</description></item><item><title>Akregator Doesn't Work on KDE's Blog</title><link>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/006-akregator-doesnt-work-on-kdes-blog/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 23:40:45 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/006-akregator-doesnt-work-on-kdes-blog/</guid><description>Small gripe.. But it seems that with a default install of KDE it the Akregator (RSS feed reader) comes pre configured with the KDE blog which doesn&amp;rsquo;t render correctly. -_-
Not that it matters it seems there isn&amp;rsquo;t any syncing ability in Akregator meaning I will stick with Miniflux for now.</description></item><item><title>Synology Office Encryption</title><link>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/005-synology-office-encryption/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 11:25:18 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/005-synology-office-encryption/</guid><description>The login process and decryption/passworded document workflow with Synology Office is not great. Probably needs to be looked at. I was going to try figure it out and provide a nice diagram of how it works, but I don&amp;rsquo;t have that much time to dedicate to this issue.
But I get stuff like this, when my login as expired, instead of just presenting a login page, it gives me this;</description></item><item><title>Aws New Glue Fail</title><link>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/004-aws-new-glue-fail/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 15:25:28 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/004-aws-new-glue-fail/</guid><description>Ugh. So it turns out AWS Glue (the new interface) when you are writing a script using the editor won&amp;rsquo;t take into account the region when you click the &amp;ldquo;cloudwatch logs&amp;rdquo; link section: I have no idea how something like this could pass. But it has. Turns out it will default to us-east-1.
It seems to only occur in certain circumstances, however&amp;hellip; Once I have selected a region post login (or acocunt switch) it works fine.</description></item><item><title>Logitech G560</title><link>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/003-logitech-g560/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 23:16:23 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/003-logitech-g560/</guid><description>So I bought a new speaker&amp;hellip; A Logitech G560.. I had been eyeing this speaker for a while. I assure you it wasn&amp;rsquo;t because of the sound changing aspect. But there wasn&amp;rsquo;t really a lot to my reasons to pick it.
One of the major points to me picking this is, in the absence of a good list of alternatives, brand loyalty. But other than that. I would have to say; Multiple input (Bluetooth, 3.</description></item><item><title>Synology Security Advisor and SSH</title><link>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/002-synology-security-ssh/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 12:12:08 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/002-synology-security-ssh/</guid><description>So I will be writing tech complaints here.. Here is the first one.
Turns out Synology defaults the SSH to port 22&amp;hellip; Then if you have enabled the security advisor it constantly complains that is set to port 22.
Why not just set it to a random (but free) port?
If you have to manually configure SSH to turn it on then you would be aware that it&amp;rsquo;s not running on a &amp;ldquo;standard&amp;rdquo; port.</description></item><item><title>First Post</title><link>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/001-first-post/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/001-first-post/</guid><description>Just creating this blog. It&amp;rsquo;s 100% a copy of: https://github.com/arran4/githubpages
But I will add stuff to it. I intend to use this space to post more technical things. Probably just tech related complaints that are more wordy than Twitter will allow.
On the plus side it&amp;rsquo;s all managed by hugo!
Want to submit improvements to the layout.. Yes. But keep them small.</description></item></channel></rss>