<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Arrans Technical blog</title><link>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Arrans Technical blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Synology Mail Reports Caught by Synology Spam Detector -- Why!?</title><link>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/025-synology-mail-reports-caught-by-synology-spam-detector-why/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 08:48:53 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/025-synology-mail-reports-caught-by-synology-spam-detector-why/</guid><description>Why!? Synology Mail Pro is decent and all. It feels like a management layer on a bunch of open source mail tools. Plus and Android app which is quite nice. However it has a bunch of quirks which make me wonder if people actually use it inside synology. Or at least various configurations.
One of the odd components of the synology mail system is the mail component isn&amp;rsquo;t fully &amp;ldquo;abstracted&amp;rdquo; between components.</description></item><item><title>Gmail and Keyboard Navigation</title><link>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/024-gmail-and-keyboard-navigation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 14:14:03 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/024-gmail-and-keyboard-navigation/</guid><description>I use the keyboard shortcuts [ and ] a lot in gmail.
However, when I do I establish a &amp;ldquo;direction&amp;rdquo; but sometimes, I press e as I want to go back to the thread list. I don&amp;rsquo;t always navigate the same direction.
For a while I turned on the &amp;ldquo;auto advance&amp;rdquo;:
Option. Today I abandoned it mostly because it doesn&amp;rsquo;t support the notion of &amp;ldquo;inertia&amp;rdquo; IMHO.. Basically I want a 3rd option that is along the lines of:</description></item><item><title>Growing Synology Wish List</title><link>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/023-growing-synology-wish-list/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 14:17:40 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/023-growing-synology-wish-list/</guid><description>I am rather fond of synologies offering however it does leave me with a couple of whishes / desires.
Synology itself Sometimes I don&amp;rsquo;t quite know if a feature is supposed to be for business or personal / private use. They often seem to have both in mind but under serve both a bit.
Anyway here are some of my opinions:
Software issues I kind of want an easier way of logging software issues.</description></item><item><title>Jetbrains and SSH Config Files</title><link>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/022-jetbrains-and-ssh-config-files/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 13:39:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/022-jetbrains-and-ssh-config-files/</guid><description>Since I have setup a Dotfiles repo using the useful Chezmoi I am using a single configuration everywhere. Something else I also do is use one account for all my work regardless of the computer I&amp;rsquo;m on.
However that means you encounter issues with software which wasn&amp;rsquo;t exactly designed for users who operate under different &amp;ldquo;aliases&amp;rdquo; on the same account. Such as, when I&amp;rsquo;m working for one of my clients, I do all my commits under the email address associated with that organisation.</description></item><item><title>Synology Cloudsync and Folder Listing</title><link>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/021-synology-cloudsync-and-folder-listing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2022 08:51:02 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/021-synology-cloudsync-and-folder-listing/</guid><description>Not sure why &amp;ldquo;Drive&amp;rdquo; gets it&amp;rsquo;s own icon but all of my cloud sync items don&amp;rsquo;t especially considering that it has all the icons already setup:</description></item><item><title>Status Bar in Browsers</title><link>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/020-status-bar-in-browsers/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 18:27:56 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/020-status-bar-in-browsers/</guid><description>While I don&amp;rsquo;t miss people using API to change the status bar text, something I can vaguely recall and I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s that useful as people don&amp;rsquo;t look there that often. (Perhaps it was for help text.)
I do seem to miss the status bar, as a concept and in browsers specifically. While it was mostly use for things such as the zoom level and SSL level, those things have been migrated to the address bar.</description></item><item><title>Signal System Tray Icon Why Doesn't It Have One?</title><link>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/019-signal-system-tray-icon-why-doesnt-it-have-one/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 18:25:58 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/019-signal-system-tray-icon-why-doesnt-it-have-one/</guid><description>Almost all the other chat clients I have can run in the background showing only a system tray icon&amp;hellip;
Why can&amp;rsquo;t Signal?
Slack Discord WhatsDesk (WhatsApp) I think:
Facebook Messenger &amp;ndash; Or it just harasses me. I guess if they did so I would hope that it at least has some marker to show that conversation has happened.</description></item><item><title>LastPass</title><link>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/018-lastpass/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 18:19:19 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/018-lastpass/</guid><description>I use a fair number of password managers for various reasons. However something that bugs me with their prompts is they don&amp;rsquo;t have a button that easily allows me to configure an exemption.. I almost never want to remember a password used on &amp;ldquo;localhost&amp;rdquo; on some weird port number because I develop software and test it frequently:
But yet it prompts me every time. There is a way I can manually configure this, Never Urls:</description></item><item><title>Simple Screen Recorder</title><link>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/017-simple-screen-recorder/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 18:14:16 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/017-simple-screen-recorder/</guid><description>SimpleScreenRecorder, the best simple screen recorder on linux that I know of.. I think it might be a wrapper around some shell commands. IDK.. But it would be nice if it were ported to other systems. Until then I use OBS which is overkill for most of what I do.. (Also in Windows Screen2Gif isn&amp;rsquo;t bad either.)
Got it working on a system with nVidia and got this error:
I don&amp;rsquo;t know what this means, what it does, or how to undo it.</description></item><item><title>Back to KDE My Observations</title><link>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/016-back-to-kde-my-observations/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 16:43:13 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/016-back-to-kde-my-observations/</guid><description>Okay having used Windows and Mac OS for a couple years. Mostly due to driver issues. (Which didn&amp;rsquo;t abate, I had to effectively buy a new computer to solve my issues. Which is rather disappointing but I think I will be moving back to a desktop / laptop hybrid model again. Laptops have disappointed me recently but that&amp;rsquo;s a conversation for another day.
Title bar customization So the move to KDE has been pretty nice in the most part.</description></item><item><title>Tools Rosetta Stone</title><link>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/015-tools-rosetta-stone/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 22:58:36 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/015-tools-rosetta-stone/</guid><description>This is mostly just a list of things to remind me what to install when I reformat / start using a new PC. But I decided I would share anyway.
The prompt for creating this table wss actually discovering ksnip which resolved a lot of my cross platform screen shot pains.
Tool Windows Linux Mac OS X Comments Screen shots ksnip ksnip ksnip Picking this up helped a lot as it was a major missing piece, I had tried things like, Shutter which became dependency hell every update as it isn&amp;rsquo;t a compiled tool and wasn&amp;rsquo;t cross platform.</description></item><item><title>Synology How Do I Update the Images Against a Tag in the Docker View?</title><link>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/014-synology-how-do-i-update-the-images-against-a-tag-in-the-docker-view/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2022 15:24:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/014-synology-how-do-i-update-the-images-against-a-tag-in-the-docker-view/</guid><description>So when you use docker with Synology it has a rather nice UI.. However it seems to be lacking things.
Such as redownloading the images for any given tag as the SHAs don&amp;rsquo;t change but the tags do! -_-
Saying that; this addition is nice: &amp;ndash;
Turns out adding itself over itself doesn&amp;rsquo;t work.
And you can&amp;rsquo;t add the update by a different tag name and switch the tag on an &amp;ldquo;off&amp;rdquo; container.</description></item><item><title>How to Prevent KDE From Starting</title><link>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/013-how-to-prevent-kde-from-starting/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2022 01:11:45 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/013-how-to-prevent-kde-from-starting/</guid><description>Turns out I could crash ksplashqml quite reliably rendering my kde setup unusable simply by having a bad XDG_DATA_DIRS configured in my .zshenv file.
I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what caused it. But it might be because it was already set, or that it ended with a :
&amp;ndash;
Edit
Actually a bit more looking around and it turns out it is if XDG_DATA_DIRS contains the same entry twice it crashes.</description></item><item><title>Minor Bug Fixes Ubuntu Deb File Recommends Error</title><link>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/012-minor-bug-fixes-ubuntu-deb-file-recommends-error/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2022 00:20:42 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/012-minor-bug-fixes-ubuntu-deb-file-recommends-error/</guid><description>Ugh..
I would rather write here that I found this issue than log it myself. Because from what I recall from the bug logging process it can be pretty tedious. Especially with bugzilla. Perhaps Github / Gitlab has spoiled me with the ability to log very simple bugs quickly and easily.
Maybe because web based interfaces were so hard to use back in the 90s, it was tedious to go through bug reports so simply reduce them by getting as much info upfront as possible including classification.</description></item><item><title>Git Bash and WSL on Windows Terminal Preview vs IntelliJ</title><link>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/011-git-bash-and-wsl-on-windows-terminal-preview-vs-intellij/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 10:03:29 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/011-git-bash-and-wsl-on-windows-terminal-preview-vs-intellij/</guid><description>For some reason IntelliJ and Windows terminal discover available shells in different ways, but either way is not ideal. (In-fact IntelliJ uses two different means of discovery.)
The terminal popup in Intellj seems to be unaware of Gitbash..
Which is in complete contrast to the terminal settings (same plugin) which is unaware of my WSL deployments. (Possibly because it&amp;rsquo;s using a file path based system) Which means I can&amp;rsquo;t set Debian WSL as my default terminal in IntelliJ.</description></item><item><title>Goland Refactor Dialog</title><link>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/010-goland-refactor-dialog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 17:17:26 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/010-goland-refactor-dialog/</guid><description>Another one from the department of should have been a bug issue: Why doesn&amp;rsquo;t the Goland &amp;ldquo;move&amp;rdquo; dialog show you the receiver. When you&amp;rsquo;re implementing a new interface this can make it a bit hard to use when you start to refactor your code.
-_-</description></item><item><title>Linux, Dmesg, and Issue Reporting</title><link>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/009-linux-dmesg-and-issue-reporting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 22:19:37 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/009-linux-dmesg-and-issue-reporting/</guid><description>So started using linux.. Getting this issue here:
[ 499.624767] thinkpad_acpi: unhandled HKEY event 0x6031 [ 499.624771] thinkpad_acpi: please report the conditions when this event happened to ibm-acpi-devel@lists.sourceforge.net [ 517.509897] thinkpad_acpi: unhandled HKEY event 0x6031 [ 517.509905] thinkpad_acpi: please report the conditions when this event happened to ibm-acpi-devel@lists.sourceforge.net I really don&amp;rsquo;t want to have to mail a mailing list and learn how to engage with the community, how to write a post, and worst yet, having to subscribe to a mailing list to get a single response.</description></item><item><title>KDE and Changing Mouse Scroll Speed</title><link>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/008-kde-and-changing-mouse-scroll-speed/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 22:02:12 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/008-kde-and-changing-mouse-scroll-speed/</guid><description>So.. Turns out the control pannel mess that exists on Windows is contagious. After 2 years of using Windows (because of driver issues) I have finally been able to switch back to Linux.. However I got used to a couple settings. One was a faster mouse scroll speed&amp;hellip; So I go to configure that and this is what I see: A quick google got me here: https://forum.kde.org/viewtopic.php?t=160416
Ugh no difference</description></item><item><title>Lenovo, Ubuntu Upgrade, and the Backport Iwlwifi Dkms Package</title><link>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/007-lenovo-ubuntu-upgrade-and-the-backport-iwlwifi-dkms-package/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 21:36:08 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/007-lenovo-ubuntu-upgrade-and-the-backport-iwlwifi-dkms-package/</guid><description>Had an issue with getting MOK to install my keys for my Intel Corporation Wi-Fi 6 AX200 (rev 1a) wireless card on my Lenovo X1 Carbon Extreme G2.. Turns out there is a bug in the shell script that installs the self signed keys in to MOX&amp;hellip; Which is great. But it turns out I have hit a bug..
Perhaps this is because I use zsh or somee other reason but.</description></item><item><title>Akregator Doesn't Work on KDE's Blog</title><link>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/006-akregator-doesnt-work-on-kdes-blog/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 23:40:45 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/006-akregator-doesnt-work-on-kdes-blog/</guid><description>Small gripe.. But it seems that with a default install of KDE it the Akregator (RSS feed reader) comes pre configured with the KDE blog which doesn&amp;rsquo;t render correctly. -_-
Not that it matters it seems there isn&amp;rsquo;t any syncing ability in Akregator meaning I will stick with Miniflux for now.</description></item><item><title>Synology Office Encryption</title><link>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/005-synology-office-encryption/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 11:25:18 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/005-synology-office-encryption/</guid><description>The login process and decryption/passworded document workflow with Synology Office is not great. Probably needs to be looked at. I was going to try figure it out and provide a nice diagram of how it works, but I don&amp;rsquo;t have that much time to dedicate to this issue.
But I get stuff like this, when my login as expired, instead of just presenting a login page, it gives me this;</description></item><item><title>Aws New Glue Fail</title><link>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/004-aws-new-glue-fail/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 15:25:28 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/004-aws-new-glue-fail/</guid><description>Ugh. So it turns out AWS Glue (the new interface) when you are writing a script using the editor won&amp;rsquo;t take into account the region when you click the &amp;ldquo;cloudwatch logs&amp;rdquo; link section: I have no idea how something like this could pass. But it has. Turns out it will default to us-east-1.
It seems to only occur in certain circumstances, however&amp;hellip; Once I have selected a region post login (or acocunt switch) it works fine.</description></item><item><title>Logitech G560</title><link>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/003-logitech-g560/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 23:16:23 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/003-logitech-g560/</guid><description>So I bought a new speaker&amp;hellip; A Logitech G560.. I had been eyeing this speaker for a while. I assure you it wasn&amp;rsquo;t because of the sound changing aspect. But there wasn&amp;rsquo;t really a lot to my reasons to pick it.
One of the major points to me picking this is, in the absence of a good list of alternatives, brand loyalty. But other than that. I would have to say; Multiple input (Bluetooth, 3.</description></item><item><title>Synology Security Advisor and SSH</title><link>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/002-synology-security-ssh/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 12:12:08 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/002-synology-security-ssh/</guid><description>So I will be writing tech complaints here.. Here is the first one.
Turns out Synology defaults the SSH to port 22&amp;hellip; Then if you have enabled the security advisor it constantly complains that is set to port 22.
Why not just set it to a random (but free) port?
If you have to manually configure SSH to turn it on then you would be aware that it&amp;rsquo;s not running on a &amp;ldquo;standard&amp;rdquo; port.</description></item><item><title>First Post</title><link>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/001-first-post/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/001-first-post/</guid><description>Just creating this blog. It&amp;rsquo;s 100% a copy of: https://github.com/arran4/githubpages
But I will add stuff to it. I intend to use this space to post more technical things. Probably just tech related complaints that are more wordy than Twitter will allow.
On the plus side it&amp;rsquo;s all managed by hugo!
Want to submit improvements to the layout.. Yes. But keep them small.</description></item></channel></rss>