<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>UI on Arrans Technical blog</title><link>https://arran4.github.io/blog/categories/ui/</link><description>Recent content in UI on Arrans Technical blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 18:27:56 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://arran4.github.io/blog/categories/ui/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Status Bar in Browsers</title><link>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/020-status-bar-in-browsers/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 18:27:56 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/020-status-bar-in-browsers/</guid><description>While I don&amp;rsquo;t miss people using API to change the status bar text, something I can vaguely recall and I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s that useful as people don&amp;rsquo;t look there that often. (Perhaps it was for help text.)
I do seem to miss the status bar, as a concept and in browsers specifically. While it was mostly use for things such as the zoom level and SSL level, those things have been migrated to the address bar.</description></item><item><title>Signal System Tray Icon Why Doesn't It Have One?</title><link>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/019-signal-system-tray-icon-why-doesnt-it-have-one/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 18:25:58 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/019-signal-system-tray-icon-why-doesnt-it-have-one/</guid><description>Almost all the other chat clients I have can run in the background showing only a system tray icon&amp;hellip;
Why can&amp;rsquo;t Signal?
Slack Discord WhatsDesk (WhatsApp) I think:
Facebook Messenger &amp;ndash; Or it just harasses me. I guess if they did so I would hope that it at least has some marker to show that conversation has happened.</description></item><item><title>LastPass</title><link>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/018-lastpass/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 18:19:19 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/018-lastpass/</guid><description>I use a fair number of password managers for various reasons. However something that bugs me with their prompts is they don&amp;rsquo;t have a button that easily allows me to configure an exemption.. I almost never want to remember a password used on &amp;ldquo;localhost&amp;rdquo; on some weird port number because I develop software and test it frequently:
But yet it prompts me every time. There is a way I can manually configure this, Never Urls:</description></item><item><title>Back to KDE My Observations</title><link>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/016-back-to-kde-my-observations/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 16:43:13 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://arran4.github.io/blog/post/2022/016-back-to-kde-my-observations/</guid><description>Okay having used Windows and Mac OS for a couple years. Mostly due to driver issues. (Which didn&amp;rsquo;t abate, I had to effectively buy a new computer to solve my issues. Which is rather disappointing but I think I will be moving back to a desktop / laptop hybrid model again. Laptops have disappointed me recently but that&amp;rsquo;s a conversation for another day.
Title bar customization So the move to KDE has been pretty nice in the most part.</description></item></channel></rss>